A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Press Materials FA1322
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Record Group 1, Accessions 2017:062 and 2017:078, 1951-2002; 1; 32.713 Cubic Feet 29 LTR size, 1 Half-LTR size, 44 LGL size, and 2 Half-LGL size Hollinger boxes and 1 oversize document box
  - Press clippings, 1964-2002; 2; 21.271 Cubic Feet About 40 LGL size Hollinger boxes, 6 LTR size Hollinger boxes, and 1 Half-LTR size Hollinger box
    - Clippings and announcements, 1992-2002; 3; 9.058 Cubic Feet About 17.25 LGL size Hollinger boxes and 2.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 February (Box 50, Folder 1270)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1998-1999 (Box 50, Folder 1271)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 January-February (Box 50, Folder 1272)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 March (Box 50, Folder 1273)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 March (Box 50, Folder 1274)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 February-March (Box 50, Folder 1275)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 April (Box 50, Folder 1276)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 March-April (Box 50, Folder 1277)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 April-May (Box 50, Folder 1278)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 May (Box 50, Folder 1279)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 May (Box 50, Folder 1280)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 May (Box 50, Folder 1281)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 June (Box 50, Folder 1282)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 June (Box 50, Folder 1283)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 June (Box 50, Folder 1284)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 July (Box 50, Folder 1285)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 July (Box 50, Folder 1286)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 July (Box 50, Folder 1287)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 August (Box 50, Folder 1288)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 August (Box 50, Folder 1289)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 August (Box 50, Folder 1290)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 September (Box 50, Folder 1291)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 September (Box 50, Folder 1292)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 September (Box 50, Folder 1293)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1998-1999 (Box 50, Folder 1294)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 January (Box 50, Folder 1295)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 February (Box 50, Folder 1296)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 June (Box 50, Folder 1297)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 June (Box 50, Folder 1298)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 July-August (Box 50, Folder 1299)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 June-July (Box 50, Folder 1300)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 August (Box 50, Folder 1301)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 August-September (Box 51, Folder 1302-1303)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 September (Box 51, Folder 1304)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 August-September (Box 51, Folder 1305)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 February (Box 51, Folder 1306)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 March (Box 51, Folder 1307)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 March (Box 51, Folder 1308)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 April (Box 51, Folder 1309)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 April-May (Box 51, Folder 1310)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 1999 May (Box 51, Folder 1311)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 May (Box 51, Folder 1312)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1998-1999 (Box 51, Folder 1313)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 January (Box 51, Folder 1314)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 February (Box 51, Folder 1315)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 January-February (Box 51, Folder 1316)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 March (Box 51, Folder 1317)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 March (Box 51, Folder 1318)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 April (Box 51, Folder 1319)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts ,and Culture (MAC), 1999 April (Box 51, Folder 1320)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 May (Box 51, Folder 1321)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 May (Box 51, Folder 1322)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 June (Box 52, Folder 1323)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 June (Box 52, Folder 1324)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 July (Box 52, Folder 1325)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 July (Box 52, Folder 1326)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 August (Box 52, Folder 1327)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 August (Box 52, Folder 1328)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 1999 September (Box 52, Folder 1329)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999 September-October (Box 52, Folder 1330)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 May (Box 52, Folder 1331-1332)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 May (Box 52, Folder 1333)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 April-May (Box 52, Folder 1334-1335)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 May (Box 52, Folder 1336)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 May (Box 52, Folder 1337)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 May (Box 52, Folder 1338)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 May (Box 52, Folder 1339)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 May (Box 52, Folder 1340-1342)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 May (Box 53, Folder 1343)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 April (Box 53, Folder 1344)
      - Education, Media, Arts and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 April (Box 53, Folder 1345)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 April (Box 53, Folder 1346)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 April (Box 53, Folder 1347)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 April (Box 53, Folder 1348)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 March-April (Box 53, Folder 1349)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 March-April (Box 53, Folder 1350)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 April (Box 53, Folder 1351)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 April-May (Box 53, Folder 1352-1353)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1354)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1355)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1356)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1357-1361)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1362)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1363)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 March-April (Box 53, Folder 1364)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1365)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 March (Box 53, Folder 1366)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 January-April (Box 54, Folder 1367-1369)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 1999-2000 (Box 54, Folder 1370)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 January-February (Box 54, Folder 1371)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 (Box 54, Folder 1372)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 February (Box 54, Folder 1373-1374)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 February (Box 54, Folder 1375)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 February (Box 54, Folder 1376)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 February (Box 54, Folder 1377)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 January-February (Box 54, Folder 1378)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1379-1382)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999-2000 (Box 54, Folder 1383)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1384)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1385)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1386)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1387)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1388)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1389)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 January (Box 54, Folder 1390)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) - Campus diversity in higher education, 1999 January (Box 55, Folder 1391)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) - Campus diversity in higher education, 1999 January-February (Box 55, Folder 1392)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) - Campus diversity in higher education, 1999 April (Box 55, Folder 1393)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) - Campus diversity in higher education, 1999 May (Box 55, Folder 1394)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC): Campus diversity in higher education, 1999 July (Box 55, Folder 1395)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 October-November (Box 55, Folder 1396-1400)
      - Past Ford Foundation Fellows, 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1401)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1402)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1403)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), circa 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1404)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1405)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1406)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1407)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 October (Box 55, Folder 1408)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 August-September (Box 55, Folder 1409)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 September-October (Box 55, Folder 1410)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 August-October (Box 55, Folder 1411)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 August-September (Box 55, Folder 1412)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 August-September (Box 55, Folder 1413)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 August-September (Box 56, Folder 1414)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 September (Box 56, Folder 1415)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 August-September (Box 56, Folder 1416)
      - Leadership for a Changing World Awards Program, 2000 September (Box 56, Folder 1417)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 September-October (Box 56, Folder 1418-1420)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 July-August (Box 56, Folder 1421-1423)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 June-August (Box 56, Folder 1424)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, circa 2000 August (Box 56, Folder 1425)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 July-August (Box 56, Folder 1426)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), circa 2000 August (Box 56, Folder 1427)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), circa 2000 August (Box 56, Folder 1428)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 August (Box 56, Folder 1429)
      - Education, Media, Arts and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 August (Box 56, Folder 1430)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts and, Culture (MAC), 2000 July-August (Box 56, Folder 1431)
      - Ford Foundation Fellows, 2000 August (Box 56, Folder 1432)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 July (Box 56, Folder 1433)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1434-1435)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 June-July (Box 57, Folder 1436)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1437)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1438)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1439)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1440)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1441)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1442)
      - Ford Foundation Fellows, 2000 July (Box 57, Folder 1443)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 2000 June (Box 57, Folder 1444)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 2000 May-June (Box 57, Folder 1445)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 2000 June (Box 57, Folder 1446)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 2000 June (Box 57, Folder 1447)
      - Ford Foundation mentions: Miscellaneous, 2000 May-June (Box 57, Folder 1448-1449)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), 2000 June-July (Box 57, Folder 1450)
      - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC), Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR), 2000 June (Box 57, Folder 1451)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 2000 June (Box 57, Folder 1452)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), 2000 June (Box 57, Folder 1453)
      - General press clips, 1996-1997 (Box 58, Folder 1454-1460)
        File contents were divided between seven folders during processing in order to better accommodate the large volume of records.
      - General press clips, 1999 December (Box 58, Folder 1461)
      - Press logs and Burrelle's and Luce announcements, 1999-2000 (Box 58, Folder 1462-1465)
      - Community Development Corporations (CDCs), 1999 (Box 59, Folder 1466)
      - Rural Community College Initiative, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 1467)
      - Clips for possible circulation, 1999 August-September (Box 59, Folder 1468)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 January (Box 59, Folder 1469)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 February (Box 59, Folder 1470)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 March (Box 59, Folder 1471)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 March-April (Box 59, Folder 1472)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 May (Box 59, Folder 1473)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 June (Box 59, Folder 1474)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 July (Box 59, Folder 1475)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 August-October (Box 59, Folder 1476)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 September (Box 59, Folder 1477)
      - Ford Foundation personnel - President Susan Berresford, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 1478)
      - Ford Foundation personnel - President Susan Berresford, 1996-1998 (Box 59, Folder 1479)
      - Ford Foundation personnel - Board of Trustees, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 1480)
      - Ford Foundation personnel - Grantees, scholarships, fellowships, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 1481-1482)
        File originally housed three subfolders. It appears that the Ford Foundation tried to group the press clippings by month, and two of the subfolders house the May 1999 and June 1999 press clippings respectively. The first subfolder holds all of the remaining press clippings. These clippings were not ordered by month.
      - Ford Foundation personnel, 1998-1999 (Box 59, Folder 1483-1484)
      - Press logs, 1998 (Box 59, Folder 1485-1486)
        File contents were divided between two folders during processing in order to better accommodate the large volume of records.
      - Luce AM Newsbreak announcements, 1998 (Box 60, Folder 1487-1488)
        Some announcements have the original press clippings attached to them.
      - Burrelle's NewsExpress announcements, 1998 July-December (Box 60, Folder 1489-1491)
      - Innovations in American Government Awards Program, 1999 October-November (Box 60, Folder 1492)
      - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society (GCS), 1999 October (Box 60, Folder 1493)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), 1999 October-November (Box 60, Folder 1494)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, 1999 October-November (Box 60, Folder 1495)
      - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, 1999 October (Box 60, Folder 1496)